<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>2018 Design Trends on On Point Custom Homes</title><link>https://onpointcustomhomes.com/blog/tag/2018-design-trends/</link><description>Recent content in 2018 Design Trends on On Point Custom Homes</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2018 05:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://onpointcustomhomes.com/blog/tag/2018-design-trends/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Design Trends Straight from the International Builder, Kitchen &#43; Bath Show: Part 3</title><link>https://onpointcustomhomes.com/blog/design-trends-straight-international-builder-kitchen-bath-show-part-3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2018 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://onpointcustomhomes.com/blog/design-trends-straight-international-builder-kitchen-bath-show-part-3/</guid><description>Trend alert – the smart home is getting even smarter! In this week’s blog post, we’re sharing some of the smartest and techy savvy products we discovered at the International Builder Show.
Whether you are building or remodeling, technology is becoming more accessible in price and easier to install and integrate throughout your house. The number one trend in smart technology is peace-of-mind. Products that allow homeowners to monitor their space and control it from afar seem to be the number one driver in innovation.</description></item><item><title>Design Trends Straight from the International Builder, Kitchen &#43; Bath Show: Part 2</title><link>https://onpointcustomhomes.com/blog/design-trends-straight-international-builder-kitchen-bath-show-part-2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2018 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://onpointcustomhomes.com/blog/design-trends-straight-international-builder-kitchen-bath-show-part-2/</guid><description>In Part II of our IBS design trends blog series, we’re sharing the feedback and highlights surrounding your home’s finishes. From countertop and tile materials to sinks and faucets, here’s what to expect in 2018.
Starting in the Kitchen, the number one trend in cabinet layout and design is the use of open shelving. More homeowners are opting for a dedicated “messy” prep space (more insight in Part 1), and with the introduction of this luxury pantry, the added storage space eliminates the need for a lot of upper cabinetry in your main kitchen.</description></item></channel></rss>