<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>houston remodel on On Point Custom Homes</title>
    <link>https://onpointcustomhomes.com/blog/tag/houston-remodel/</link>
    <description>Recent content in houston remodel on On Point Custom Homes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Sep 2018 04:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://onpointcustomhomes.com/blog/tag/houston-remodel/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Designing Your Perfect Built-Ins &amp; Cabinets</title>
      <link>https://onpointcustomhomes.com/blog/designing-your-perfect-built-ins-cabinets/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Sep 2018 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://onpointcustomhomes.com/blog/designing-your-perfect-built-ins-cabinets/</guid>
      <description>One of the most common remodeling requests is the addition of built-ins. Not only do they add a focal point to the space, but built-ins also give you the opportunity to enhance your storage with the addition of new cabinetry. Adding or updating built-ins and cabinetry can make an enormous impact on your home’s aesthetic. That being said, there are endless styles when it comes to cabinetry design, so we’re breaking down what you need to know to get started.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Briargrove Southern Charm Remodel: Part 4</title>
      <link>https://onpointcustomhomes.com/blog/briargrove-southern-charm-remodel-part-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Apr 2018 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://onpointcustomhomes.com/blog/briargrove-southern-charm-remodel-part-4/</guid>
      <description>In our final reveal of this major remodel project, we’re talking all about the outdoors. With spring weather in full swing, you’ll be daydreaming about this stunning exterior transformation for days.
Without altering the architecture of the existing home, we modernized the facade with a fresh coat of paint. We removed the shutters and opted for a clean transitional aesthetic. The doors remained the same; however, they also received new paint.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Briargrove Southern Charm Remodel: Part 2</title>
      <link>https://onpointcustomhomes.com/blog/briargrove-southern-charm-remodel-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Mar 2018 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://onpointcustomhomes.com/blog/briargrove-southern-charm-remodel-part-2/</guid>
      <description>Who doesn’t love a kitchen makeover?! This Briargrove home had a good footprint but needed some remodel love to make the room feel more timeless. On Point resurfaced the entire room to transform this family’s kitchen from drab to fab.
All new paint, countertops, hardware, lighting, and sink + faucet goes a long way! Take a look at the final product below.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Briargrove Southern Charm Remodel: Part 1</title>
      <link>https://onpointcustomhomes.com/blog/briargrove-southern-charm-remodel-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Mar 2018 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://onpointcustomhomes.com/blog/briargrove-southern-charm-remodel-part-1/</guid>
      <description>On Point is known for our custom design + build program; however, we also love helping clients transform their existing home with major remodel projects! In this three-part series, we’re showing you the before and afters of this Briargrove home that needed a major facelift.
On Point took on the challenge of updating this house without altering the overall footprint. We did update every surface, fixture and finish for the entire interior and exterior and came back and added a freestanding outdoor entertaining space complete with a wood-burning fireplace, surround sound, TV and ample seating.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>