<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>On Point on On Point Custom Homes</title>
    <link>https://onpointcustomhomes.com/blog/tag/on-point/</link>
    <description>Recent content in On Point on On Point Custom Homes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://onpointcustomhomes.com/blog/tag/on-point/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Turf &#43; Xeriscaping - How to Create a Maintenance </title>
      <link>https://onpointcustomhomes.com/blog/turf_xeriscaping/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jul 2020 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://onpointcustomhomes.com/blog/turf_xeriscaping/</guid>
      <description>One thing all Texans can agree on is just how unpredictable the weather here can be. Knowing how to navigate these weather changes when it comes to maintaining a yard can become a huge hassle for homeowners. However, there are many landscaping options that can eliminate or reduce the need for serious maintenance in your yard.
Turf is a great option for those looking for a virtually maintenance-free yard. Making the decision to install turf instead of grass in your yard may seem costly, however, you actually end up saving far more in the long run when you eliminate the need for sprinkler systems or yard work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Design Trends Straight from the International Builder, Kitchen &#43; Bath Show: Part 1</title>
      <link>https://onpointcustomhomes.com/blog/design-trends-straight-international-builder-kitchen-bath-show-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2018 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://onpointcustomhomes.com/blog/design-trends-straight-international-builder-kitchen-bath-show-part-1/</guid>
      <description>At On Point Custom Homes, we truly believe in exploring new ideas and staying ahead of the curve when it comes to architectural design, product integration, and building science. We make it a point to attend a variety of industry shows across the county throughout the year in order to keep our team apart of conversations in the building space and in front of the latest and greatest products. Most recently our CEO, President, Selections Coordinator, Purchasing Manager and Marketing Director took a trip to Orlando to attend the National Association of Home Builders International Builder Show as well as the Kitchen and Bath Show.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>