<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blogs on On Point Custom Homes</title>
    <link>https://onpointcustomhomes.com/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blogs on On Point Custom Homes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Aug 2020 05:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://onpointcustomhomes.com/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Designing the Perfect At Home Student Station</title>
      <link>https://onpointcustomhomes.com/blog/desks/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Aug 2020 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://onpointcustomhomes.com/blog/desks/</guid>
      <description>![](https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/6Wsv72nB_GVolxNdQu-seiC_iMCDJdk96UGX-AwywboA9bZp8r89LzsYSvnlIjNEnyizUMY-rU8EKvP8RlmKakm_O0F8RvWQvh1xAGi7H33NEkK0iYYUfXfmiVrwkrL1CCczLV6j =624x805)
The Coronavirus pandemic has forced the world to make changes and adapt in virtually all aspects of life. With the school year quickly approaching, it is becoming more and more apparent that school may look very different for young students this year. With that in mind, it is very important that your children have a space that makes adapting to zoom schooling a little easier and helps separate their work and school space from the rest of your home.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upgrade your HVAC for purer air</title>
      <link>https://onpointcustomhomes.com/blog/hvacpurerair/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2020 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://onpointcustomhomes.com/blog/hvacpurerair/</guid>
      <description>This article was published in the _Houston Chronicle. _
Now more than ever, we are all hyper-aware of all things health and wellness. Due to the COVID-19 pandemic, there is a heightened awareness of and desire to remain as healthy and clean as possible, both inside and out. While it can be difficult to control what you are coming into contact with when out in public, there is a solution for avoiding unwanted bacteria, germs, allergens, and pollutants in your home — install an air purification system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Texas Association of Builders 2020 Award Wins!</title>
      <link>https://onpointcustomhomes.com/blog/2020tabawards/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jul 2020 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://onpointcustomhomes.com/blog/2020tabawards/</guid>
      <description>We look forward to the Texas Association of Builders STAR awards every year! Usually our team packs up and heads to the Sunbelt Builder Show for the trade show and award ceremony, but this year looked a bit different! While we couldn&amp;rsquo;t explore the trade show and award ceremony in person this year, it didn&amp;rsquo;t stop our team from celebrating our big wins!
This year we were honored to take home FIVE Awards for design + marketing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Turf &#43; Xeriscaping - How to Create a Maintenance </title>
      <link>https://onpointcustomhomes.com/blog/turf_xeriscaping/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jul 2020 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://onpointcustomhomes.com/blog/turf_xeriscaping/</guid>
      <description>One thing all Texans can agree on is just how unpredictable the weather here can be. Knowing how to navigate these weather changes when it comes to maintaining a yard can become a huge hassle for homeowners. However, there are many landscaping options that can eliminate or reduce the need for serious maintenance in your yard.
Turf is a great option for those looking for a virtually maintenance-free yard. Making the decision to install turf instead of grass in your yard may seem costly, however, you actually end up saving far more in the long run when you eliminate the need for sprinkler systems or yard work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Join us on the MA&#43;DS Modern Home Tour!</title>
      <link>https://onpointcustomhomes.com/blog/madshometour/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Mar 2020 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://onpointcustomhomes.com/blog/madshometour/</guid>
      <description>We are thrilled to once again partake in the MA+DS Modern Home Tour! This year&amp;rsquo;s tour is Saturday, March 28 from 11 a.m. - 5 p.m. and you can purchase tickets online here. Use code ONPOINT2020 for $5 off!
Meet the team that designed + built 2300 South Blvd and tour this amazing modern home that is ADA compliant home!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Love Design?! We&#39;re Looking for a Selections Specialist! </title>
      <link>https://onpointcustomhomes.com/blog/selectionsspecialist/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2020 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://onpointcustomhomes.com/blog/selectionsspecialist/</guid>
      <description>We are looking for an enthusiastic individual to join our team to lead selection management and client concierge services. Ideal candidate has a passion for design and thrives in a collaborative, fast-paced office environment. Three years of residential design experience required. Construction and purchasing experience preferred. This position entails the following:
Job responsibilities include the following:
 Lead all internal spec home selections, collaborating with the Architectural team, to design a unique design package for every On Point spec home Lead all custom clients through the selections process ensuring an exceptional experience while remaining on schedule, this includes providing design guidance and inspiration, detailed timelines for selection needs, scheduling show room visits, coordinating vendor/client meetings and executing selection sign offs Assist Architectural and Purchasing teams with specifications for spec and custom homes Provide status updates to clients throughout the design + build process, serving as the main point of contact for all client needs Send selection and change order requests to clients for sign-off Present clients with design inspiration and create all design portfolio booklets for spec homes Manage vendor receivables and bids as it relates to selection needs Manage vendor relationships and product knowledge base Create home warranty packets for homeowners Assist with purchasing takeoffs and bids, as needed Execute purchase orders, as needed  Job requires the following skills:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We&#39;re Hiring! Real Estate Marketing &#43; Sales Associate</title>
      <link>https://onpointcustomhomes.com/blog/hiringsales/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2020 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://onpointcustomhomes.com/blog/hiringsales/</guid>
      <description>We are looking for an individual for a marketing + sales associate position with a desire to learn more about the residential real estate industry to assist and support our sales + marketing team. Ideal candidate has at least 2-years of previous employment or internship experience in an office setting. Marketing experience and a passion for real estate required.
Job responsibilities include the following:
 Create and execute engaging and creative monthly marketing campaigns for multiple online platforms including Facebook, LinkedIn, Instagram, email marketing and blogs Manage client database and oversee lead generation and marketing efforts Manage and update website(s), blog(s), email marketing pieces and online social media accounts regularly to promote active listings, service offerings and overall enhancement of agent’s and company’s social media presence Create engaging text, image and video content for online platforms to drive marketing and sales efforts and showcase company news and culture Work with sales principals to prepare all listing materials: pre-listing presentation, listing agreement, sellers’ disclosures, comparative market analysis, pull online property profile, research old multiple listing service (MLS) listings, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Come Work With Us! Now Hiring an Accounting Specialist</title>
      <link>https://onpointcustomhomes.com/blog/accountingspecialist/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2019 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://onpointcustomhomes.com/blog/accountingspecialist/</guid>
      <description>We are in search of an enthusiastic accounting professional to oversee and manage all office accounting tasks including, but not limited to, accounts receivables/payables, analysis of financial statements and various financial reporting for multiple entities. Candidate must be extremely proficient in QuickBooks. This position would be responsible for the following:
 Oversee Accounts Payables and Accounts Receivables Update cash flow forecasts on a weekly basis Work with Banks/Clients to create and manage Draw Schedules for multiple projects Perform weekly bank draws for multiple projects, provide the appropriate backup, and serve as the main point of contact for the multiple banks Responsible for managing Variance Reporting Responsible for managing all audits and reconciliations Analyze and complete financial statements for multiple entities Capable of both completing all transactions in QuickBooks for multiple entities including journal entries for month end and quarter end close.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Earl &#43; Dana Visit Indy for Master Builder Meeting</title>
      <link>https://onpointcustomhomes.com/blog/master-building-meeting/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://onpointcustomhomes.com/blog/master-building-meeting/</guid>
      <description>Earl and Dana represented On Point for the Spring 2019 session of the Master Builders hosted by the enterprising owners and staff at Gradison Design-Build. Twice a year, a members invite-only group of construction industry leaders from the United States and Caribbean gather to share three days and nights of intensive sessions consisting of financial overviews, round-table discussions, best practices discussion forums, innovative construction techniques, the latest in applied technology and software, material sourcing and pricing, project reviews, site tours, vendor showcases and shared camaraderie.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Basics of Building: Pre-Wiring &#43; Smart Home Tech</title>
      <link>https://onpointcustomhomes.com/blog/basics-of-building-pre-wiring-smart-home-tech/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Oct 2018 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://onpointcustomhomes.com/blog/basics-of-building-pre-wiring-smart-home-tech/</guid>
      <description>These days “smart home” is at the top of many homeowner’s wish list and at On Point, part of our mission is to always stay ahead of the building curve and embrace emerging technology, so our homes are never behind the times. While you may think of Nest, Eco Bee, Alexa and Ring when you think of smart homes, On Point’s integration of smart technology goes much further than being install-ready for trending tech products.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NEW AWARDS FROM THE GHBA!</title>
      <link>https://onpointcustomhomes.com/blog/new-awards-from-the-ghba/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Oct 2018 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://onpointcustomhomes.com/blog/new-awards-from-the-ghba/</guid>
      <description>The office is looking a bit shinier this week! As many of you know, On Point is a proud member of the Greater Houston Builder’s Association and has been since we started building. One of our favorite annual company traditions is the GHBA PRISM Awards + Gala! Over the last ten+ years, we’ve won multiple design and marketing awards and the streak continues.
We were honored to bring home six “Houston’s Best” awards and were finalists in six additional categories.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Designing Your Perfect Built-Ins &amp; Cabinets</title>
      <link>https://onpointcustomhomes.com/blog/designing-your-perfect-built-ins-cabinets/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Sep 2018 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://onpointcustomhomes.com/blog/designing-your-perfect-built-ins-cabinets/</guid>
      <description>One of the most common remodeling requests is the addition of built-ins. Not only do they add a focal point to the space, but built-ins also give you the opportunity to enhance your storage with the addition of new cabinetry. Adding or updating built-ins and cabinetry can make an enormous impact on your home’s aesthetic. That being said, there are endless styles when it comes to cabinetry design, so we’re breaking down what you need to know to get started.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Basics of Building: Insulation</title>
      <link>https://onpointcustomhomes.com/blog/basics-of-building-insulation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2018 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://onpointcustomhomes.com/blog/basics-of-building-insulation/</guid>
      <description>We’ve officially gotten through the worst of Houston’s hot and humid summer, but I’m sure many of you are still enjoying the luxury of a great air conditioning system as we creep info fall. You can have a great HVAC system, but it only goes so far without proper insulation. We’re dropping some knowledge on how we handle insulating our homes to ensure it’s as energy efficient as possible to keep your home’s temperature regulated all year long.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Join the Team - Now Hiring for an Architectural Designer</title>
      <link>https://onpointcustomhomes.com/blog/join-team-now-hiring-architectural-designer-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Aug 2018 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://onpointcustomhomes.com/blog/join-team-now-hiring-architectural-designer-2/</guid>
      <description>Position: Architectural Designer
**Location:**Houston, TX
**Key Responsibilities
**We are looking for an individual with a Bachelor’s of Architecture who is interested in residential construction and custom home building. This specific degree is preferred; however please note that favor may be given to those with a higher degree or level of accreditation. At least one year of formal work experience is preferred, and more than that is favored. This individual must be:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Awards from the Texas Association of Builders</title>
      <link>https://onpointcustomhomes.com/blog/new-awards-from-the-texas-association-of-builders/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Aug 2018 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://onpointcustomhomes.com/blog/new-awards-from-the-texas-association-of-builders/</guid>
      <description>If you follow the adventures of On Point on Facebook and Instagram, you’ve probably heard the news already, but if not, we’re excited to share that our team brought home some new hardware from the Texas Association of Builders! And by hardware, we mean awards, although we probably brought back some actual hardware samples, too.
Garrett, Tiffany and Ashley spent the last half of last week in Dallas attending the Sunbelt Builders Show put on by the Texas Association of Builders.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Dec My Room</title>
      <link>https://onpointcustomhomes.com/blog/introducing-dec-my-room/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://onpointcustomhomes.com/blog/introducing-dec-my-room/</guid>
      <description>As you guys know, On Point makes it a point to support our community and give back both with time and charitable contributions. Throughout our history, we’ve worked with a variety of local and national organizations to give back in different ways. We have a longstanding history with Habitat for Humanity, Houston Food Bank and Candlelighters and last year had the amazing opportunity to work with the Ronald McDonald House of Houston to design + build a custom playhouse for the residents of the home.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Basics of Building: Windows</title>
      <link>https://onpointcustomhomes.com/blog/basics-of-building-windows/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jul 2018 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://onpointcustomhomes.com/blog/basics-of-building-windows/</guid>
      <description>Windows play an important role in your home as their various styles, materials and colors will significantly impact the architectural design and overall aesthetic. More importantly, they also are a significant piece of your home’s energy efficiency puzzle.
With today’s energy codes, all the windows going into our new homes are double paned with a gas insulation. We believe in going above and beyond minimum standards, so all of our windows use a high-grade performance low-e glass.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Designing in 3D Why it Makes a Difference</title>
      <link>https://onpointcustomhomes.com/blog/designing-in-3d-why-it-makes-a-difference/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jul 2018 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://onpointcustomhomes.com/blog/designing-in-3d-why-it-makes-a-difference/</guid>
      <description>Too often people are surprised to hear we offer in-house architectural design services in addition to building and remodeling. Not only do we offer architecture services, but we utilize a 3D design software that most residential teams don’t take advantage of. Designing all of our plans in 3D is a win-win for everyone involved as it brings a set of plans to life before an ounce of dirt is moved.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Basics of Building: Housewrap &#43; Rainscreens</title>
      <link>https://onpointcustomhomes.com/blog/basics-of-building-housewrap-rainscreens/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2018 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://onpointcustomhomes.com/blog/basics-of-building-housewrap-rainscreens/</guid>
      <description>Protecting your home from water is paramount to your home’s lifespan. Investing in products that protect against the inevitable water penetration can have lasting impacts on the longevity of your home. In this week’s Basics of Building series, we’re diving into water barrier protection plans with housewrap and rainscreens.
First up – Housewrap. To you it looks like we’ve wrapped your home in some fancy plastic cling wrap, but the reality is that cling wrap is your number one defense against water damage.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Products from Thermador &#43; Bosch</title>
      <link>https://onpointcustomhomes.com/blog/new-products-from-thermador-bosch/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jul 2018 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://onpointcustomhomes.com/blog/new-products-from-thermador-bosch/</guid>
      <description>Last week our Selections Coordinator extraordinaire, Tiffany, spent the week in Chicago learning all about two of our favorite appliance brands, Thermador and Bosch, newest luxury product lines. In fact, we love them both so much almost every home we build has one, if not both, in the appliance packages. Not only did Tiffany get a first look at the new products coming out this fall and beyond, but she also got some serious lessons in both steam oven and induction cooking, two trends that are taking off in kitchen design.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Basics of Building: Foundation Fundamentals Part 3</title>
      <link>https://onpointcustomhomes.com/blog/basics-of-building-foundation-fundamentals-part-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jul 2018 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://onpointcustomhomes.com/blog/basics-of-building-foundation-fundamentals-part-3/</guid>
      <description>In our final Foundation Fundamentals series, we’re talking about a foundation that is most commonly known to homeowners as a Pier and Beam foundation. We call it a Crawl-Space Foundation and use it most often when clients are in a floodplain and require an elevated home.
**Crawl-Space Foundation
**For those of you who live in a floodplain (hello to our friends in Meyerland + Bellaire!) you need a Crawl-Space Foundation. This is a typical pier and beam foundation, which elevates the home leaving a crawl-space underneath.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Basics of Building: Foundation Fundamentals Part 2</title>
      <link>https://onpointcustomhomes.com/blog/basics-of-building-foundation-fundamentals-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jun 2018 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://onpointcustomhomes.com/blog/basics-of-building-foundation-fundamentals-part-2/</guid>
      <description>We’re continuing the great debate of foundations with everything you need to know about a Post Tension Slab. Take a look at Part 1 of our Basics of Building series to learn more about building science and what we do differently from other builders.
**Post Tension Slab
**If you are looking for a more cost-effective foundation, consider using a Post Tension Slab. In this technique, you eliminate the need for piers with the addition of beams and tension cables that provide extra stability.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Basics of Building: Foundation Fundamentals Part 1</title>
      <link>https://onpointcustomhomes.com/blog/basics-of-building-foundation-fundamentals-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jun 2018 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://onpointcustomhomes.com/blog/basics-of-building-foundation-fundamentals-part-1/</guid>
      <description>Ever wonder exactly how your home is being put together – what techniques, products and systems are being used? And what makes one technique better than another? We’re breaking down the basics of building science to help you understand how your home is actually being constructed and sharing what we do differently from other builders. Without bogging you down with too much minutiae, we’ll explain various techniques and share the differences, pros and cons of each.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Perfect Party Ready Backyard</title>
      <link>https://onpointcustomhomes.com/blog/the-perfect-party-ready-backyard/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jun 2018 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://onpointcustomhomes.com/blog/the-perfect-party-ready-backyard/</guid>
      <description>We recently hosted the most colorful backyard party anyone has ever seen with Ashley Rose from Sugar &amp;amp; Cloth. While we didn’t do it alone, we did do something by ourselves before all the pool floats, balloon banners and yummy treats showed up – and that was design + build this pool and outdoor space for a family who loves to entertain. Thinking about updating your backyard space? Keep reading for our advice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bringing Together the Perfect Modern Farmhouse Design</title>
      <link>https://onpointcustomhomes.com/blog/bringing-together-the-perfect-modern-farmhouse-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 May 2018 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://onpointcustomhomes.com/blog/bringing-together-the-perfect-modern-farmhouse-design/</guid>
      <description>We recently completed a modern farmhouse in Oak Forest that may be one of our favorite projects this year! The home started as an inventory home but was purchased mid-construction turning the adorable 4 bedroom, 3.5 bath family home into a semi-custom job. With modern farmhouse style continuing to grow in popularity, take a look below for tips from our team on capturing this style.
Five Tips for Achieving the Modern Farmhouse Look…</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Briargrove Southern Charm Remodel: Part 4</title>
      <link>https://onpointcustomhomes.com/blog/briargrove-southern-charm-remodel-part-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Apr 2018 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://onpointcustomhomes.com/blog/briargrove-southern-charm-remodel-part-4/</guid>
      <description>In our final reveal of this major remodel project, we’re talking all about the outdoors. With spring weather in full swing, you’ll be daydreaming about this stunning exterior transformation for days.
Without altering the architecture of the existing home, we modernized the facade with a fresh coat of paint. We removed the shutters and opted for a clean transitional aesthetic. The doors remained the same; however, they also received new paint.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Briargrove Southern Charm Remodel: Part 3</title>
      <link>https://onpointcustomhomes.com/blog/briargrove-southern-charm-remodel-part-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Apr 2018 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://onpointcustomhomes.com/blog/briargrove-southern-charm-remodel-part-3/</guid>
      <description>In case you missed the first two posts about this Briargrove whole-home remodel, take a look here! When we took on this project the overall layout of the home did not need many changes; however, the finishes were ready for some updates. In this week’s series, we’re sharing the before and afters of the bedrooms and bathrooms. The home featured a kid’s study nook with built-ins that we ripped out in order to transform the space for added functionality for a nursery.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Briargrove Southern Charm Remodel: Part 2</title>
      <link>https://onpointcustomhomes.com/blog/briargrove-southern-charm-remodel-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Mar 2018 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://onpointcustomhomes.com/blog/briargrove-southern-charm-remodel-part-2/</guid>
      <description>Who doesn’t love a kitchen makeover?! This Briargrove home had a good footprint but needed some remodel love to make the room feel more timeless. On Point resurfaced the entire room to transform this family’s kitchen from drab to fab.
All new paint, countertops, hardware, lighting, and sink + faucet goes a long way! Take a look at the final product below.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Briargrove Southern Charm Remodel: Part 1</title>
      <link>https://onpointcustomhomes.com/blog/briargrove-southern-charm-remodel-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Mar 2018 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://onpointcustomhomes.com/blog/briargrove-southern-charm-remodel-part-1/</guid>
      <description>On Point is known for our custom design + build program; however, we also love helping clients transform their existing home with major remodel projects! In this three-part series, we’re showing you the before and afters of this Briargrove home that needed a major facelift.
On Point took on the challenge of updating this house without altering the overall footprint. We did update every surface, fixture and finish for the entire interior and exterior and came back and added a freestanding outdoor entertaining space complete with a wood-burning fireplace, surround sound, TV and ample seating.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>National Women in Construction Week!</title>
      <link>https://onpointcustomhomes.com/blog/national-women-construction-week/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Mar 2018 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://onpointcustomhomes.com/blog/national-women-construction-week/</guid>
      <description>Who runs the world? Girls! It’s officially National Women in Construction Week and we’re celebrating the fabulously talented ladies in the office! If you haven’t had the pleasure of working with them yet, you can get to know them a bit better below!
Our Selections Coordinator, Tiffany, has been in the industry for more than 18 years and with us for more than 10! She is the third generation in her family to pursue a career in the Houston construction industry.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2015 &#43; 2016 Flood Victims Rebuild Meyerland Modern 5 Feet Up</title>
      <link>https://onpointcustomhomes.com/blog/2015-2016-flood-victims-rebuild-meyerland-modern-5-feet/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Feb 2018 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://onpointcustomhomes.com/blog/2015-2016-flood-victims-rebuild-meyerland-modern-5-feet/</guid>
      <description>Located in the heart of Meyerland, this brand new custom home was designed and built five feet off the ground after our clients endured not one, but two floods in their prior one-story ranch.
After purchasing and remodeling the home, the home was stuck in the 2015 Memorial Day flood. They reached out to On Point shortly after looking for guidance on whether a second remodel or a complete rebuild made the most sense.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Design Trends Straight from the International Builder, Kitchen &#43; Bath Show: Part 3</title>
      <link>https://onpointcustomhomes.com/blog/design-trends-straight-international-builder-kitchen-bath-show-part-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2018 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://onpointcustomhomes.com/blog/design-trends-straight-international-builder-kitchen-bath-show-part-3/</guid>
      <description>Trend alert – the smart home is getting even smarter! In this week’s blog post, we’re sharing some of the smartest and techy savvy products we discovered at the International Builder Show.
Whether you are building or remodeling, technology is becoming more accessible in price and easier to install and integrate throughout your house. The number one trend in smart technology is peace-of-mind. Products that allow homeowners to monitor their space and control it from afar seem to be the number one driver in innovation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Design Trends Straight from the International Builder, Kitchen &#43; Bath Show: Part 2</title>
      <link>https://onpointcustomhomes.com/blog/design-trends-straight-international-builder-kitchen-bath-show-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2018 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://onpointcustomhomes.com/blog/design-trends-straight-international-builder-kitchen-bath-show-part-2/</guid>
      <description>In Part II of our IBS design trends blog series, we’re sharing the feedback and highlights surrounding your home’s finishes. From countertop and tile materials to sinks and faucets, here’s what to expect in 2018.
Starting in the Kitchen, the number one trend in cabinet layout and design is the use of open shelving. More homeowners are opting for a dedicated “messy” prep space (more insight in Part 1), and with the introduction of this luxury pantry, the added storage space eliminates the need for a lot of upper cabinetry in your main kitchen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Design Trends Straight from the International Builder, Kitchen &#43; Bath Show: Part 1</title>
      <link>https://onpointcustomhomes.com/blog/design-trends-straight-international-builder-kitchen-bath-show-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2018 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://onpointcustomhomes.com/blog/design-trends-straight-international-builder-kitchen-bath-show-part-1/</guid>
      <description>At On Point Custom Homes, we truly believe in exploring new ideas and staying ahead of the curve when it comes to architectural design, product integration, and building science. We make it a point to attend a variety of industry shows across the county throughout the year in order to keep our team apart of conversations in the building space and in front of the latest and greatest products. Most recently our CEO, President, Selections Coordinator, Purchasing Manager and Marketing Director took a trip to Orlando to attend the National Association of Home Builders International Builder Show as well as the Kitchen and Bath Show.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GHBA Best Custom Home Elevation Winner</title>
      <link>https://onpointcustomhomes.com/blog/ghba-best-custom-home-elevation-winner/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2013 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://onpointcustomhomes.com/blog/ghba-best-custom-home-elevation-winner/</guid>
      <description>On Point Custom Homes is proud to share the news of our 2009 GHBA award for Houston’s Best Custom Home Elevation for our recently completed design at 2246 Branard!! Earl recently accepted this award on 9/12/09 at a formal event hosted by the GHBA. We are truly excited and honored to be the 2009 recipient of this prestigious local award!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2424 Hazard Review</title>
      <link>https://onpointcustomhomes.com/blog/2424-hazard-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jun 2013 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://onpointcustomhomes.com/blog/2424-hazard-review/</guid>
      <description>Review of our latest smarthome at 2424 Hazard by KTRH connected reporter, Michelle Merhar!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do you build modern homes in Houston?</title>
      <link>https://onpointcustomhomes.com/blog/do-you-build-modern-homes-in-houston/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2013 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://onpointcustomhomes.com/blog/do-you-build-modern-homes-in-houston/</guid>
      <description>On Point Custom Homes considers itself one of the pioneers of Houston modern homes. Our first modern Houston home was in 2005 when very few competitors would venture into this realm. We have seen a demand for our Houston modern homes grown over the years and field many calls for both our inventory homes as well as custom homes. If you wish to schedule a consultation with one of our staff regarding a custom home, please call On Point Custom Homes at 713-600-2422.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Does On Point Custom Homes use green building?</title>
      <link>https://onpointcustomhomes.com/blog/does-on-point-custom-homes-use-green-building/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2013 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://onpointcustomhomes.com/blog/does-on-point-custom-homes-use-green-building/</guid>
      <description>We are asked this question with more and more regularity. On Point Custom Homes is proud to have a staff member, Earl Correll, who has earned his certified green professional (CGP) designation through the National Association of Home Builders (NAHB). Through this designation, we are able to provide valuable insight to our custom home clients that wish to adopt green principles into their home. Also, we strive to add green building techniques into our inventory homes as we find environmentally friendly products that can enhance both our quality and finished product.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is a radiant barrier on residential roof decking?</title>
      <link>https://onpointcustomhomes.com/blog/what-is-a-radiant-barrier-on-residential-roof-decking/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Feb 2013 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://onpointcustomhomes.com/blog/what-is-a-radiant-barrier-on-residential-roof-decking/</guid>
      <description>We all know about the Houston, TX heat!! The primary reason to install a radiant barrier is reduce heat gain in the Summer and heat loss in the Winter. This is accomplished by reflecting the suns rays back toward the actual roof and not allowing them fully to penetrate the attic space.
There are many different applications for radiant barriers in residential attics. On new construction custom homes, the most common is for On Point Custom Homes is to install roof decking with the radiant barrier attached to the bottom of the decking.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why are NAHB designations important?</title>
      <link>https://onpointcustomhomes.com/blog/why-are-nahb-designations-important/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Jan 2013 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://onpointcustomhomes.com/blog/why-are-nahb-designations-important/</guid>
      <description>You may have seen a builder with initials after their name on a business card and often asked what that pertains to. It likely is an accreditation earned through the National Association of Home Builders (NAHB). These accreditations demonstrate a builders commitment to continuing education, customer service and an overall understanding of today’s dynamic home building industry.
On Point Custom Homes commitment to these ideals is recognized in our staff’s ability to earn Certified Graduate Builder (CGB) degrees through the NAHB.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Does On Point Custom Homes do remodeling?</title>
      <link>https://onpointcustomhomes.com/blog/does-on-point-custom-homes-do-remodeling/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Dec 2012 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://onpointcustomhomes.com/blog/does-on-point-custom-homes-do-remodeling/</guid>
      <description>We are often asked about this by past clients and potential clients. The answer is Yes! During the first five months of 2009, On Point Custom Homes has completed 7 remodels and currently working on 4 additional jobs. Many of our current remodels are damaged homes on the Texas coasts from Hurricane Ike. We have jobs in Galveston, La Porte, Shore Acres, Bolivar Peninsula and Houston’s Inner Loop. At On Point, we have taken pride in helping bring Texas families back to their homes post storm.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why is quartz gaining popularity in Houston homes?</title>
      <link>https://onpointcustomhomes.com/blog/why-is-quartz-gaining-popularity-in-houston-homes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Nov 2012 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://onpointcustomhomes.com/blog/why-is-quartz-gaining-popularity-in-houston-homes/</guid>
      <description>On Point Custom Homes uses quartz in many of our modern Houston homes. Clients often ask why we use quartz…there are many reasons, but let’s cover some of the top reasons.
  We believe quartz gives a more modern touch to a contemporary style home than granite. It has a clean overall feel and modern enthusiasts seem to be gravitating toward quartz countertops.
  Ease of mainteance. Quite simply On Point Custom Homes recommends a damp cloth with warm water and soap to wipe down quartz.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do you install mosquito systems in Houston?</title>
      <link>https://onpointcustomhomes.com/blog/do-you-install-mosquito-systems-in-houston/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Oct 2012 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://onpointcustomhomes.com/blog/do-you-install-mosquito-systems-in-houston/</guid>
      <description>Summer in Houston usually brings homeowners outside to take in the pleasures of their yards. A familiar issue is mosquitoes and how to manage them, and a Houston mosquito system solution is becoming a necessity. On Point Custom Homes is prepared to assist by offering a Mosquito Lock System. This innovative system allows homeowners complete control of their yard by spraying a very fine mist in intervals set on a controller, and is the most desired Houston mosquito system available.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do you build in Briargrove neighborhood in Houston, TX?</title>
      <link>https://onpointcustomhomes.com/blog/do-you-build-in-briargrove-neighborhood-in-houston-tx/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Sep 2012 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://onpointcustomhomes.com/blog/do-you-build-in-briargrove-neighborhood-in-houston-tx/</guid>
      <description>On Point Custom Homes has built several Houston custom homes within the Briargrove subdivision. Established in the 1950’s, this neighborhood is highly sought-after by home buyers. Briargrove boasts in-town living with easy access to Houston’s shopping districts and entertainment venues, and is considered to be one of the most family-oriented neighborhoods in Houston. Residents enjoy a strong homeowners association and share a clubhouse, play area, pool and the award-winning Briargrove elementary.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I see a lot of your signs in the River Oaks Shopping Center area...how much do you build there?</title>
      <link>https://onpointcustomhomes.com/blog/i-see-a-lot-of-your-signs-in-the-river-oaks-shopping-center-area-how-much-do-you-build-there/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Aug 2012 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://onpointcustomhomes.com/blog/i-see-a-lot-of-your-signs-in-the-river-oaks-shopping-center-area-how-much-do-you-build-there/</guid>
      <description>The area surrounding the River Oaks Shopping Center is home to many On Point Custom Homes designs. This historic area, located at the geographic center of Houston, offers urban living and a unique balance of nationally recognized stores, eclectic shops, and an abundance of dining options. Bordered by the Museum District to the South, Midtown and and the Downtown Theater District to the East, and River Oaks to the West, this prominent neighborhood is lined with Houston custom homesembracing a definite eclectic nature.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is there a particular type of home that best suits Houston modern furniture styles?</title>
      <link>https://onpointcustomhomes.com/blog/is-there-a-particular-type-of-home-that-best-suits-houston-modern-furniture-styles/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jun 2012 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://onpointcustomhomes.com/blog/is-there-a-particular-type-of-home-that-best-suits-houston-modern-furniture-styles/</guid>
      <description>With a great many changes in the way that home décor and home decorating is completed, there really isn’t any home that doesn’t suit modern furniture design. Houston modern furniture, like that found in all other major cities, is going to range from those styles with ethnic or cultural influences through to the ultra-modern and minimalist styles. There are several furniture stores that feature Danish or Scandinavian modern styles that look wonderful in any type of home.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What defines a Houston modern home?</title>
      <link>https://onpointcustomhomes.com/blog/what-defines-a-houston-modern-home/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 May 2012 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://onpointcustomhomes.com/blog/what-defines-a-houston-modern-home/</guid>
      <description>Houston itself is really a very old city, first founded in 1836 and then incorporated the very next year. It has modest beginnings until 1901 when it became a major oil producing area as well as a railway hub. The increasing workforce that these two types of industry brought into the then small town led to very rapid growth and the demand for both economic and luxury types of homes. Houston modern homes are not considered to be these original structures, although many of the plantation style mansions still gloriously line the streets of the older parts of the city.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Are there several options with regards to Houston modern luxury homes and residences?</title>
      <link>https://onpointcustomhomes.com/blog/are-there-several-options-with-regards-to-houston-modern-luxury-homes-and-residences/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Apr 2012 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://onpointcustomhomes.com/blog/are-there-several-options-with-regards-to-houston-modern-luxury-homes-and-residences/</guid>
      <description>Houston modern luxury homes, townhomes, patio homes and condos offer an amazing range of options. This may include where they are located, what perks come with the residence and what shopping, parks, schools or other community attractions are in the area.
Typically Houston modern luxury townhomes and patio homes will have cutting edge design options and push the future of architectural design. If in a luxury complex, the will most typically have beautifully landscaped areas with green spaces, trees for shade and even a cocktail pool.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>All I see in Houston is one story ranch style houses, are there any modern inner city Patio Homes?</title>
      <link>https://onpointcustomhomes.com/blog/all-i-see-in-houston-is-one-story-ranch-style-houses-are-there-any-modern-inner-city-patio-homes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Mar 2012 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://onpointcustomhomes.com/blog/all-i-see-in-houston-is-one-story-ranch-style-houses-are-there-any-modern-inner-city-patio-homes/</guid>
      <description>There are a great number of different styles and architectural design options in the Houston modern patio homes on the market today. Some are two story, some offer high, unique ceilings, while others offer incredible open design options. These luxury homes, many which are designed specifically for the Houston modern patio home styles, offer the most variety when it comes to both interior and exterior style options.
Many builders specializing in Houston modern patio homes will provide the option for the buyer to work with the builder to customize the patio home.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I heard you won the 2009 Pacesetter Award, can you tell me about it?</title>
      <link>https://onpointcustomhomes.com/blog/i-heard-you-won-the-2009-pacesetter-award-can-you-tell-me-about-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Mar 2012 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://onpointcustomhomes.com/blog/i-heard-you-won-the-2009-pacesetter-award-can-you-tell-me-about-it/</guid>
      <description>On Point Custom Homes was the recipient of the 2009 Pacesetter Award given out by Custom Home Magazine in conjunction with Hanley Wood and the NAHB. Each year, this prestigious award is given to approximately 10 builders across the country that exceed and define excellence in the home building industry.
Only 8 builders across the country received this acclimation in 2008. On Point Custom Homes was the only builder to win this award from the State of Texas.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why a Houston Patio Home?</title>
      <link>https://onpointcustomhomes.com/blog/why-a-houston-patio-home/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2012 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://onpointcustomhomes.com/blog/why-a-houston-patio-home/</guid>
      <description>Houston modern patio homes offer the “lock and leave” lifestyle.
Lock and leave is a term often used by Realtors and marketers when describing the positive attributes or features of Houston modern patio homes. This term means that the owners can simply lock up and leave the home, which is important for those that travel for business or enjoy an easy maintenance lifestyle. The lower cost of owning a Houston modern patio home makes these home types a great option for people that only want to live in Texas for part of the year, who have kids leaving for college and want to downsize or want to live in a trendy location.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mosquito Time in Houston!</title>
      <link>https://onpointcustomhomes.com/blog/mosquito-time-in-houston/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jan 2012 03:50:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://onpointcustomhomes.com/blog/mosquito-time-in-houston/</guid>
      <description>One of the most treasured company events of the year is our epic Secret Santa showdown! We’re one big happy family and we love getting each other crazy, creative gifts. Check out the goods!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>