<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Building Science on Example</title>
    <link>https://onpointcustomhomes.netlify.com/blog/tag/building-science/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Building Science on Example</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2018 04:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://onpointcustomhomes.netlify.com/blog/tag/building-science/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Basics of Building: Insulation</title>
      <link>https://onpointcustomhomes.netlify.com/blog/basics-of-building-insulation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2018 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://onpointcustomhomes.netlify.com/blog/basics-of-building-insulation/</guid>
      <description>We’ve officially gotten through the worst of Houston’s hot and humid summer, but I’m sure many of you are still enjoying the luxury of a great air conditioning system as we creep info fall. You can have a great HVAC system, but it only goes so far without proper insulation. We’re dropping some knowledge on how we handle insulating our homes to ensure it’s as energy efficient as possible to keep your home’s temperature regulated all year long.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Basics of Building: Windows</title>
      <link>https://onpointcustomhomes.netlify.com/blog/basics-of-building-windows/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jul 2018 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://onpointcustomhomes.netlify.com/blog/basics-of-building-windows/</guid>
      <description>Windows play an important role in your home as their various styles, materials and colors will significantly impact the architectural design and overall aesthetic. More importantly, they also are a significant piece of your home’s energy efficiency puzzle.
With today’s energy codes, all the windows going into our new homes are double paned with a gas insulation. We believe in going above and beyond minimum standards, so all of our windows use a high-grade performance low-e glass.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Basics of Building: Housewrap &#43; Rainscreens</title>
      <link>https://onpointcustomhomes.netlify.com/blog/basics-of-building-housewrap-rainscreens/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2018 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://onpointcustomhomes.netlify.com/blog/basics-of-building-housewrap-rainscreens/</guid>
      <description>Protecting your home from water is paramount to your home’s lifespan. Investing in products that protect against the inevitable water penetration can have lasting impacts on the longevity of your home. In this week’s Basics of Building series, we’re diving into water barrier protection plans with housewrap and rainscreens.
First up – Housewrap. To you it looks like we’ve wrapped your home in some fancy plastic cling wrap, but the reality is that cling wrap is your number one defense against water damage.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Basics of Building: Foundation Fundamentals Part 2</title>
      <link>https://onpointcustomhomes.netlify.com/blog/basics-of-building-foundation-fundamentals-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jun 2018 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://onpointcustomhomes.netlify.com/blog/basics-of-building-foundation-fundamentals-part-2/</guid>
      <description>We’re continuing the great debate of foundations with everything you need to know about a Post Tension Slab. Take a look at Part 1 of our Basics of Building series to learn more about building science and what we do differently from other builders.
**Post Tension Slab
**If you are looking for a more cost-effective foundation, consider using a Post Tension Slab. In this technique, you eliminate the need for piers with the addition of beams and tension cables that provide extra stability.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Basics of Building: Foundation Fundamentals Part 1</title>
      <link>https://onpointcustomhomes.netlify.com/blog/basics-of-building-foundation-fundamentals-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jun 2018 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://onpointcustomhomes.netlify.com/blog/basics-of-building-foundation-fundamentals-part-1/</guid>
      <description>Ever wonder exactly how your home is being put together – what techniques, products and systems are being used? And what makes one technique better than another? We’re breaking down the basics of building science to help you understand how your home is actually being constructed and sharing what we do differently from other builders. Without bogging you down with too much minutiae, we’ll explain various techniques and share the differences, pros and cons of each.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>