<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Personnels on On Point Custom Homes</title>
    <link>https://onpointcustomhomes.com/personnel/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Personnels on On Point Custom Homes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 12:00:17 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://onpointcustomhomes.com/personnel/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>JOHN LEGGETT</title>
      <link>https://onpointcustomhomes.com/personnel/john-leggett/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 12:00:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://onpointcustomhomes.com/personnel/john-leggett/</guid>
      <description>Growing up in North Carolina, John’s introduction to the residential construction industry began as a young boy when his father, an airline pilot, decided to pursue a personal interest and start a construction company. John would often tag along with his father visiting job sites, and quickly became a regular fixture where he started learning the ins and outs of residential construction.
John attended the University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill, where he received his Masters in Accounting and BS in Business Administration from the Kenan-Flagler Business School.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>EARL CORRELL</title>
      <link>https://onpointcustomhomes.com/personnel/earl-correll/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Apr 2019 06:00:17 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://onpointcustomhomes.com/personnel/earl-correll/</guid>
      <description>Growing up with On Point’s founder John Leggett, Earl became interested in being a builder while spending summers working with his uncle who ran a construction business, and while watching his own family build their home.
While pursuing a general contractors license in North Carolina Earl accepted the opportunity to move out to Houston and join the On Point team in 2006. Since his arrival in Houston, he has received his Graduate Master Builder and Certified Green Professional designations from the National Association of Home Builders.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ROBERT APPELGATE</title>
      <link>https://onpointcustomhomes.com/personnel/robert-appelgate/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2019 05:00:17 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://onpointcustomhomes.com/personnel/robert-appelgate/</guid>
      <description>Robert was born and raised just North of Houston making him a true born and raised Texan. Some of his earliest childhood memories include tagging along to work with his father, who worked in the home remodeling business. As he grew older, these experiences lead him to pursue a career in the construction industry with his first role being in the design and wiring of home theatre systems. During the ten years he spent in the industry managing various levels of residential projects, technology was evolving giving Robert a creative edge and insight into the smart home revolution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ASHLEY TUCKER</title>
      <link>https://onpointcustomhomes.com/personnel/ashley-tucker/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Apr 2019 04:00:17 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://onpointcustomhomes.com/personnel/ashley-tucker/</guid>
      <description>An overly-organized project management specialist, Ashley has a passion for all things operations related. You won’t find her without her to-do list and colored-coded pens in hand. Ashley’s eagerness and enthusiasm makes it easy for her to take on challenges, find solutions and get the job done no matter what the circumstance.
Ashley brings a variety of strategic project management and communications experience to On Point Custom Homes. From non-profit experience to agency life, Ashley has worked with a multitude of local and national businesses helping them reach their business goals through strategic and integrated operational efforts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>KAYLA PHILBROOK</title>
      <link>https://onpointcustomhomes.com/personnel/kayla-philbrook/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2019 06:00:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://onpointcustomhomes.com/personnel/kayla-philbrook/</guid>
      <description>Kayla is a proud Texan, born and raised. She grew up on the coast in a small town “across the bridge” from Corpus Christi. From an early age, Kayla was fascinated with building and designing things, spending time helping her dad build anything they could get their hands on. She gained a passion for architecture after years of walking through open houses with her mom. She would critique the houses, pointing out what could have been done better, and always knew that her calling in life was for architectural design.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Maria Mast</title>
      <link>https://onpointcustomhomes.com/personnel/mariamast/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2019 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://onpointcustomhomes.com/personnel/mariamast/</guid>
      <description>Maria Mast graduated with honors from the University Of Illinois where she earned a B.S. in Architectural Studies. Wanting to round out her architectural education she attended Texas A&amp;amp;M University where she graduated top five in her class and earned a Master of Architecture Degree and a degree certificate in sustainable urbanism.
During her studies, Maria’s main design focus was sustainable residential design and the quadruple bottom line; a holistic design approach that addresses the economic, social, ecological, and sensual demands of any project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ALBERT AGUIRRE</title>
      <link>https://onpointcustomhomes.com/personnel/albert-aguirre/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2019 23:00:17 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://onpointcustomhomes.com/personnel/albert-aguirre/</guid>
      <description>Albert is a native Houstonian, and is the third generation in his family to work in residential construction. Unlike most teenagers, Albert’s free time included joining his father and uncle working as contractors on the weekends learning a wide variety of trades. Albert further developed his skillset after graduation over years managing and working on various residential projects before joining the On Point Custom Homes team in 2016.
Albert’s role includes managing our remodel projects as well as supporting our field operations in any way possible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LE TRAN</title>
      <link>https://onpointcustomhomes.com/personnel/le/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2019 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://onpointcustomhomes.com/personnel/le/</guid>
      <description>After finishing high school in Vietnam, Le and her family migrated to the US in 2006. Having to start over and re-learn everything from language to culture and lifestyle, she learned that perseverance and hard work is nothing to be afraid of. Le studied at the University of Houston while working full-time to fund her education. Shortly after graduating from college, she started her career in the Oil &amp;amp; Gas industry and slowly work her way up the corporate ladder.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ROSIE ROMERO</title>
      <link>https://onpointcustomhomes.com/personnel/rosie/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 1999 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://onpointcustomhomes.com/personnel/rosie/</guid>
      <description>While Rosie officially joined the On Point family in 2019, she has been a part of the team for many years. Working as a Real Estate Assistant alongside Leah Leggett, Rosie assisted on hundreds of our transactions over the years learning the ins and outs of the business. From leasing to staging and beyond, she has been a part of all phases of the real estate transaction. You’ll still find her today visiting job sites and staging our homes.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>