<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Personnels on Example</title>
    <link>https://onpointcustomhomes.netlify.com/personnel/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Personnels on Example</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2019 01:39:30 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://onpointcustomhomes.netlify.com/personnel/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>DANA WALKER</title>
      <link>https://onpointcustomhomes.netlify.com/personnel/dana-walker/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2019 01:39:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://onpointcustomhomes.netlify.com/personnel/dana-walker/</guid>
      <description>Dana is no stranger to the homebuilding industry, in fact she often jokes that the homebuilding industry chose her. Coming from a family of humbly skilled craftsman, who together built their family’s lake house, barn, and various custom furniture pieces, is one of the reasons she made her way into the industry.
After joining a Houston-area custom builder shortly after graduating from the University of North Texas, she had the opportunity to work in various departments of the business from bidding and purchasing to permitting and accounting and eventually worked her way up to the selections team where she collaborated with architects and homeowners on interior finishes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>EVAN DARR</title>
      <link>https://onpointcustomhomes.netlify.com/personnel/evan-darr/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2019 01:38:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://onpointcustomhomes.netlify.com/personnel/evan-darr/</guid>
      <description>I was born and raised in Columbus, Texas; a small rural town about 60 miles West of Houston. Construction is in my blood as I grew up assisting my dad on many job sites helping him with building homes, remodeling, and doing all types of construction. When not tagging along on construction site visits, I played football, was on the powerlifting team and was active in Boy Scouts. After graduating high school, I attended Blinn College in Brenham and transferred to Sam Houston State University where I received a Bachelor of Business Administration in Finance and a minor in Banking.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ALBERT AGUIRRE</title>
      <link>https://onpointcustomhomes.netlify.com/personnel/albert-aguirre/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2019 01:37:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://onpointcustomhomes.netlify.com/personnel/albert-aguirre/</guid>
      <description>Albert is a native Houstonian, and is the third generation in his family to work in residential construction. Unlike most teenagers, Albert’s free time included joining his father and uncle working as contractors on the weekends learning a wide variety of trades. Albert further developed his skillset after graduation over years managing and working on various residential projects before joining the On Point Custom Homes team in 2016.
Albert’s role includes managing our remodel projects as well as supporting our field operations in any way possible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BRAD WILLIAMS</title>
      <link>https://onpointcustomhomes.netlify.com/personnel/brad-williams/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2019 01:36:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://onpointcustomhomes.netlify.com/personnel/brad-williams/</guid>
      <description>Brad comes from a long line of craftsman, as both his father and grandfather were carpenters, so it’s no surprise that Brad has a natural ability when it comes to building. While he grew up all over the country traveling from city to city as an Army brat, but now proudly calls Houston home. Brad started his career with a production builder overseeing job sites and managing the construction process in some of Houston’s popular suburban communities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WILL HERMANN, AIA</title>
      <link>https://onpointcustomhomes.netlify.com/personnel/will-hermann/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2019 01:35:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://onpointcustomhomes.netlify.com/personnel/will-hermann/</guid>
      <description>Will was born and raised in Northwest Houston. From a young age he enjoyed taking apart and rebuilding anything he could get his hands on. This combined with his predilection for art prompted him to take drafting classes and led to his passion for Architecture. Will went on to get his Bachelor’s in Architecture from the University of Texas at Austin, where he focused on designing sustainable architecture with a Texas climate in mind.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GARRETT NANCE</title>
      <link>https://onpointcustomhomes.netlify.com/personnel/garrett-nance/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2019 01:34:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://onpointcustomhomes.netlify.com/personnel/garrett-nance/</guid>
      <description>Garrett was born and raised just south of Houston in Pearland, Texas. He was introduced to the construction industry in High School when he worked for a local commercial construction company during school breaks and summers. Garrett attended Texas A&amp;amp;M University where he earned his BBA in Finance. After graduation, he began working for a top residential builder in Houston as an estimator, where he learned the process behind budgeting homes as well as identifying cost savings opportunities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TIFFANY TRASK</title>
      <link>https://onpointcustomhomes.netlify.com/personnel/tiffany-trask/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2019 01:33:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://onpointcustomhomes.netlify.com/personnel/tiffany-trask/</guid>
      <description>Tiffany was born in Denver, CO, but moved as a child and grew up in Clear Lake, TX. She is the third generation in her family to pursue a career in the Houston construction industry. Her career began on the commercial side in the accounting department of her father’s company. In this role, she built her foundation on construction elements and timeline from the inside out. After deciding to pursue her interest the residential construction field, Tiffany proceeded to work for a custom builder and land development company where she found her strengths best suited to assist both the Project Management and Accounting departments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ASHLEY TUCKER</title>
      <link>https://onpointcustomhomes.netlify.com/personnel/ashley-tucker/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2019 01:32:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://onpointcustomhomes.netlify.com/personnel/ashley-tucker/</guid>
      <description>An overly-organized project management specialist, Ashley has a passion for all things operations related. You won’t find her without her to-do list and colored-coded pens in hand. Ashley’s eagerness and enthusiasm makes it easy for her to take on challenges, find solutions and get the job done no matter what the circumstance.
Ashley brings a variety of strategic project management and communications experience to On Point Custom Homes. From non-profit experience to agency life, Ashley has worked with a multitude of local and national businesses helping them reach their business goals through strategic and integrated operational efforts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ROBERT APPELGATE</title>
      <link>https://onpointcustomhomes.netlify.com/personnel/robert-appelgate/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2019 01:31:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://onpointcustomhomes.netlify.com/personnel/robert-appelgate/</guid>
      <description>Robert was born and raised just North of Houston making him a true born and raised Texan. Some of his earliest childhood memories include tagging along to work with his father, who worked in the home remodeling business. As he grew older, these experiences lead him to pursue a career in the construction industry with his first role being in the design and wiring of home theatre systems. During the ten years he spent in the industry managing various levels of residential projects, technology was evolving giving Robert a creative edge and insight into the smart home revolution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>EARL CORRELL</title>
      <link>https://onpointcustomhomes.netlify.com/personnel/earl-correll/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2019 01:27:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://onpointcustomhomes.netlify.com/personnel/earl-correll/</guid>
      <description>Growing up with On Point’s founder John Leggett, Earl became interested in being a builder while spending summers working with his uncle who ran a construction business, and while watching his own family build their home.
While pursuing a general contractors license in North Carolina Earl accepted the opportunity to move out to Houston and join the On Point team in 2006. Since his arrival in Houston, he has received his Graduate Master Builder and Certified Green Professional designations from the National Association of Home Builders.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>John Leggett</title>
      <link>https://onpointcustomhomes.netlify.com/personnel/john-leggett/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2019 02:50:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://onpointcustomhomes.netlify.com/personnel/john-leggett/</guid>
      <description>Growing up in North Carolina, John’s introduction to the residential construction industry began as a young boy when his father, an airline pilot, decided to pursue a personal interest and start a construction company. John would often tag along with his father visiting job sites, and quickly became a regular fixture where he started learning the ins and outs of residential construction.
John attended the University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill, where he received his Masters in Accounting and BS in Business Administration from the Kenan-Flagler Business School.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>